http://www.heidelberg.com/global/en/global_content/privacy_statement.jsp

Corporate
Australia Austria Belgium Brazil Canada China Czech Republic Denmark Estonia Finland France Germany Greece Hungary India Indonesia Italy Japan Korea Latvia Lithuania Malaysia Mexico Netherlands New Zealand Philippines Poland Russia Singapore Slovakia South Africa Spain Sweden Switzerland Taiwan Thailand Turkey United Kingdom United States
Select country
Website Shop
EN
DE
ES
FR
Website Shop
×
×
Format 35 x 50 Format 50 X 70 Format 70 X 100 Format 100 x 140 and 120 x 160 Peripherals Press control systems Computer-to-plate
Narrow web printing
Narrow web printing
×
Conventional label printing Digital label printing
Screen printing
Screen printing
×
Rotary screen printing Flat screen printing
×
Cutting machines High-speed cutters Cutting systems Label cutting
Die-cutting and embossing
Die-cutting and embossing
×
Die-cutting machines Rotary die-cutters
Folding
Folding
×
Folding machines Feeder Delivery Modules Options & accessories Robotics
Inspection
Inspection
×
Inline Offline
Folding carton gluing
Folding carton gluing
×
Folding carton gluers Peripherals
×
Lifecycle Smart & Plus Subscription Smart & Plus Stand-alone agreements
Parts & labor
Parts & labor
×
Service parts & repair Maintenance Upgrades
Color management Installation & relocation
Remote services
Remote services
×
Remote diagnosis & expert support eCall Predictive Monitoring
Digital platforms
Digital platforms
×
Heidelberg Cloud Heidelberg Assistant Heidelberg App Online Training Prinect Smart BI eShop
Training & Consulting
Training & Consulting
×
Training programs Consulting services
Consumables
Consumables
×
Consumables portfolio Special applications LE UV & LED UV application support
Financing
Financing
×
Financial services Investment planning
IPA free printing
Software
Software
×
Workflow
Workflow
×
Prinect Business Prinect Production Success stories Prinect downloads
Industrial solutions
Industrial solutions
×
Production solutions
Production solutions
×
Foundry Manufacturing Assembly Surface engineering Industrial Maintenance Electronics
Print solutions
Print solutions
×
Printed electronics Industrial Printing
eMobility
eMobility
×
Heidelberg Wallbox Home Eco Heidelberg Wallbox Energy Control FAQ Heidelberg Wallbox
Solutions for the print industry
Solutions for the print industry
×
Folding Box Production Label Production Commercial Production
Solutions for digitalization
About us
About us
×
Company
Company
×
Company profile Executive bodies Sustainability Corporate governance Compliance Find your partner (worldwide) Production sites Suppliers Print Media Center Social Media
Investor relations
Investor relations
×
Capital market & stock information Financing/Bonds Financial publications Annual general meeting IR calendar Contact & order form
Career
Career
×
Your career at Heidelberg Vocational training Studies Internships & thesis Graduates & professionals Jobsearch
Public relations
Public relations
×
Press releases PR team Press kits Media library
News & events
News & events
×
Upcoming events Customer magazine Podcast #We4You
Offset printing
Format 35 x 50Format 50 X 70Format 70 X 100Format 100 x 140 and 120 x 160PeripheralsPress control systemsComputer-to-plate
Narrow web printing
Conventional label printingDigital label printing
Screen printing
Rotary screen printingFlat screen printing
Inline-flexo printing
Remarketed equipment
Speedmaster - Colors of success
Finishing×
Cutting
Cutting machinesHigh-speed cuttersCutting systemsLabel cutting
Die-cutting and embossing
Die-cutting machinesRotary die-cutters
Folding
Folding machinesFeederDeliveryModulesOptions & accessoriesRobotics
Inspection
InlineOffline
Folding carton gluing
Folding carton gluersPeripherals
Hot foil stamping
The world of packaging is yours
Services & consumables×
Contracts
Lifecycle Smart & PlusSubscription Smart & PlusStand-alone agreements
Parts & labor
Service parts & repairMaintenanceUpgrades Color managementInstallation & relocation
Remote services
Remote diagnosis & expert supporteCallPredictive Monitoring
Digital platforms
Heidelberg CloudHeidelberg AssistantHeidelberg AppOnline TrainingPrinect Smart BIeShop
Training & Consulting
Training programsConsulting services
Consumables
Consumables portfolioSpecial applicationsLE UV & LED UV application support
Financing
Financial servicesInvestment planning
IPA free printing
Software×
Workflow
Prinect BusinessPrinect ProductionSuccess storiesPrinect downloadsIndustrial solutions×
Production solutions
FoundryManufacturingAssemblySurface engineeringIndustrial MaintenanceElectronics
Print solutions
Printed electronicsIndustrial Printing
eMobility
Heidelberg Wallbox Home EcoHeidelberg Wallbox Energy ControlFAQ Heidelberg Wallbox
Solutions for the print industry
Folding Box ProductionLabel ProductionCommercial Production
Solutions for digitalization
About us×
Company
Company profileExecutive bodiesSustainabilityCorporate governanceComplianceFind your partner (worldwide)Production sitesSuppliersPrint Media CenterSocial Media
Investor relations
Capital market & stock informationFinancing/BondsFinancial publicationsAnnual general meetingIR calendarContact & order form
Career
Your career at HeidelbergVocational trainingStudiesInternships & thesisGraduates & professionalsJobsearch
Public relations
Press releasesPR teamPress kitsMedia library
News & events
Upcoming eventsCustomer magazinePodcast#We4You
#PressingAhead
#InnovationWeek
Further information on data processing
Social Media
Essential cookies
Functional cookies
Marketing cookies
Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG Privacy Statement.
If you wish to make use of special services of our company via our website or the apps or if you order something via our eShop, the processing of personal data may become necessary. If the processing of personal data is necessary and there is no legal basis for such processing (for example, the implementation of a contractual agreement), we will ask for your consent.This Privacy Statement contains information about the data we collect from you, how we use it and how you can object to the use of this data.
Who is responsible for data collection and processing?
Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG welcomes your visit to our web pages and app and your interest in our products. Please note that this Privacy Statement no longer applies if you follow links to third-party sites or register in areas controlled by other data controllers. The data controller with respect to this website or app is:Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AGGutenbergring69168 WieslochGermanyTel.: +49 (0)6221 92 00Our data protection officer can be contacted at:Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AGData Protection OfficerGutenbergring69168 WieslochGermanyE-mail: Datenschutzbeauftragter@heidelberg.com
Why do we process your data (processing purpose) and what is the legal basis for this?
In the following, we will give you a general overview of the processing purposes and legal bases in the context of our web pages and app. We have collected more detailed information for you below, sorted by the tools used. For technical reasons, certain data must be collected and stored when you visit our web pages, such as the date and duration of your visit, the web pages used, the identification data of the type of browser and operating system used and the website from which you are visiting us.In order to fulfill a contract, we require certain personal data from you. This data is required to make bookings in the eShop, process payments, carry out credit checks, deliver to the specified address (if items are to be shipped) and, where appropriate, to process cancellations or refunds.In this case, the contract is the legal basis for the processing of your personal data in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR also applies in respect of processing operations that are necessary for carrying out pre-contractual measures, for example in the event of inquiries regarding our products or services.If we obtain your consent for the processing of personal data (for example, if you sign up for the newsletter or use the “stay signed in” option), this serves as the legal basis in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. If our company is subject to a legal obligation rendering the processing of personal data necessary, for example in order to meet tax obligations, the processing is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR. In order to constantly improve the services we offer you, we store and analyze usage data from the online area on a pseudonymized basis. The legal basis for this is our legitimate interest in the optimization of our web pages and apps, and in the effective design of our advertising in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. Only applies to existing customers: We are also interested in maintaining our customer relationship with you and in providing you with information and offerings that we believe match your interests. We therefore process your data on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR (also with the help of service providers) in order to send you information and offerings. We use your contact data (name and e-mail address that we have received from our business relationship with you) for advertising by post and for market research, unless you object to such use.
On what legal grounds are cookies used and are there options for opting out?
We use cookies, tracking tools, targeting methods and social media plug-ins for our website/application. These enable us to make visiting our web pages more attractive, prevent cases of misuse, e.g. in the context of our eShop, and facilitate the use of certain functions. Exactly which procedures are involved and how your data is used for this purpose is explained below in the information on the respective service. The cookies can be categorized as follows: Essential cookies: These technologies are required to activate the core functionality of the website and to achieve the objective of the website. These cookies are necessary for technical reasons so that you can visit our website and use the respective functions. The legal basis of the processing for the above-mentioned purposes is your and our legitimate interest in providing you with a functioning website and relevant content in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 lit. f GDPR.Functional cookies: Functional cookies are used to operate the site and enable convenient handling as part of the user experience. The legal basis of the processing for the above-mentioned purposes is your and our legitimate interest in facilitating a convenient user experience in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 lit. f GDPR.Marketing cookies: Marketing, analysis and targeting cookies are typically used to improve the service on our web pages or to show you advertisements that match your interests. The legal basis for this is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 lit. a GDPR. If additional legal bases exist, these are indicated under the respective service. You may object to the processing of your data and the use of cookies, as set out under paragraphs 1. and 2. above, if there are overriding interests that prevent processing. In this case, however, the functionality of the website will be severely limited. You may revoke your consent to the processing of your data and the use of cookies, as set out under paragraph 3., at any time with effect for the future. You will find the link for opting out from marketing and statistics cookies by moving your mouse over here and for adjusting your settings by moving your mouse over here. Cookies are small text files that are automatically created by your browser and stored on your terminal device (laptop, tablet, smartphone, etc.) when you visit our website. Information in connection with the specific terminal device used is stored in the cookie, however this does not mean that we can obtain direct knowledge of your identity as a result.
To whom will your data be passed on?
Internal transfer of personal data: Heidelberg's internal IT departments and the selected service providers engaged by them can access user data insofar as this is necessary in the course of fulfilling their tasks. Orders for information material via the app or our contact form are handed over to Heidelberg’s marketing team or sales team as part of lead management. Transfers to third parties:Personal data is usually transferred to third parties in the context of our web pages and apps if their services are deliberately used or accessed by the user. More detailed, additional or different information, such as further recipients or the transfer to third countries, can be found below under the details of the respective service.
How long will your data be stored?
Personal data that we process on the basis of consent will be processed by us for as long as the wording of the consent allows or until the consent of the data subject is revoked. We store tax-relevant personal data for ten years, pursuant to the first sentence of Section 147 para. 3 of the German Fiscal Code (AO), the first half sentence of Section 257 para. 4 of the German Commercial Code (HGB) in conjunction with Section 257 para. 1 nos. 1 and 4 HGB, and sentences 1 and 2 of Section 14b para. 1 of the German VAT Act (UStG). We store personal data on user accounts/master data, for push notifications, and for the allocation of performance data on the basis of our legitimate interest in defending or asserting legal claims up to their limitation period for three years from the end of the year in which the processing was carried out, pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR and Sections 280 para. 1, 195, and 199 para. 1 of the German Civil Code (BGB). Due to our legitimate interest in security and troubleshooting, we store personal communication data and protocols for a maximum of seven days from the end of processing, pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. We store personal analysis and statistical data, such as Google Analytics data relating to user behavior, only for as long as this is necessary in order to create the anonymized data records. This corresponds to a deletion within a very short time. We may also store your data for a longer period of time if necessary, for example to assert or defend legal claims, solve technical problems, or analyze security incidents. Erasure of dataWe always erase personal data when there is no requirement for further storage. A requirement may exist in particular if the data is still needed to fulfill contractual services, or so that we can check and allow or fend off warranty claims and, if applicable, guarantee claims. In the event of statutory retention obligations, the data can only be erased after the respective retention obligation has expired.
What rights do data subjects have?
We do not carry out profiling or automated decision making in the normal course of business. We expressly refer to exceptions under the respective headings below. You have various rights under the GDPR as a user* of our app: In accordance with Art. 15 GDPR, you can request information about the personal data relating to you that we process. When requesting this information, you should outline your concern more precisely in order to make it easier for us to compile the necessary data. If the legal requirements of Art. 15 para. 3 or Art. 20 GDPR are met, you have the right to receive a copy of your data or to have your data transferred to you. If the information concerning you is not (or no longer) correct, you can request a correction in accordance with Art. 16 GDPR. If your data is incomplete, you can request that it be completed. You can request the deletion of your personal data under the provisions of Art. 17 GDPR. Within the framework of the provisions of Art. 18 GDPR, you have the right to request that the processing of data concerning you be restricted. Where data is processed on the basis of legitimate interests, you have the right under Art. 21 GDPR to object at any time to the processing of data concerning you for reasons arising from your particular situation. You may object to the processing of your personal data on the basis of legitimate interests for direct marketing purposes at any time without giving reasons. You can revoke your consent at any time with future effect. You may assert these rights against Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG free of charge via the e-mail address or postal address stated above. Please feel free to contact us first before you make use of your right to lodge a complaint with the data protection supervisory authorities. Our competent data protection supervisory authority is: “The State Commissioner for Data Protection and Freedom of Information” in Baden-Württemberg.
Further information on data processing when using various services can be found here:
Event and product information
The Heidelberg Group may make the following personal data available to you on web pages or in the app: Personal data about speakers, presenters at trade fairs and events (e.g. date of the event, duration of the speech, content of the speech, name of the speaker, brief profile of the speaker). Speakers can be external persons or employees of the Heidelberg Group.Personal data on contact persons and experts at trade fairs and events (such as people's names, their position at Heidelberg, information on special expertise, business contact details, etc.). We receive this data on a voluntary basis directly from the people concerned and use it for advertising or information purposes only after express consent and approval has been given. The legal basis for processing this data (information on speakers and contacts) is the consent of the data subjects pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.
Use of the Heidelberg Assistant and the app
If you register to use the Heidelberg Assistant, you will be asked to provide the following information: last name, first name, e-mail address, country, and customer affiliation. Providing the information is voluntary. If you provide us with this information, we will use it to identify users and to make personal and individual content of the app visible.If users receive a voucher from us, these vouchers will be assigned to user e-mail addresses and displayed within the app, provided that the user logs into the app with this e-mail address. We receive the e-mail address via the registration; the allocation of vouchers by HDM AG and its Sales and Service Center.When you set up the app, you will be asked if the app is allowed to send you notifications. If you agree, we will use push notifications to send you alerts about the app, as well as marketing messages. The service then sends the registration ID (Android) or the token (iOS) to the registered device. The app sends the ID or token to the server, where it is stored in a database. If a push notification is to be sent, the server sends the desired message with registration ID/token to the platform’s push service, which forwards the push notification to the respective devices. You can suspend receipt of push notifications when not using the app by explicitly logging out of the app.You can revoke your consent to receive push notifications via the operating system as follows: iOS/Settings//NotificationsAndroid/Settings/Applications/Applications Manager//Notifications When you use our app, the data that is sent by your browser during usage and that is required to use our services is automatically recorded. This data includes the IP address, installation ID, operating system, platform (iOS, Android, Windows), and the date and time of use of our services. Every time our app is used or a file stored in the app is retrieved, this action is logged.The following is logged: name of the retrieved file, date and time of retrieval, amount of data transferred, notification of successful retrieval, app ID and requesting domain. The IP addresses of the requesting devices are also logged. Access is registered for reasons of data security, to ensure the stability and operational reliability of our system and to protect against possible external attacks. In addition, the data is statistically evaluated to optimize the services we offer. It is not possible to trace which contents you have accessed or which files you have retrieved on the basis of the logged data. The temporary collection of the data is necessary in order to enable the delivery of the content to the terminal devices and to guarantee its reproduction. This data is not merged with other data sources. The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose for which it was collected. For the storage of data in log files, this is the case after seven days at the latest. It is possible that the data may additionally be stored with our technical service providers for statistical purposes, inter alia. In this case, the IP address will be deleted or masked so that the calling device can no longer be assigned. The collection of data for the provision of the app and its storage is absolutely necessary for the operation of the service, so that there is no option for the user to object. The legal basis for the processing of user account/master data and the assignment of performance data and communication data is the fulfillment of our contract with you for the provision of the Heidelberg Assistant and your content in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR. The legal basis for the processing of push notifications, and for information and marketing purposes, is our legitimate interest in providing users with relevant information about the Heidelberg Group in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. In addition, we use the Google Firebase service for our app to analyze and categorize user groups, and to send push notifications. You can find more information here, at Google, or directly in our app.
Use of the Heidelberg Innovation Week Site
On the Innovation Week site, the following tools are used to provide you with professional digital support. When you register for Innovation Week, enter your e-mail address in the input mask on the website. A confirmation e-mail will then be sent to the e-mail address you entered, in which you must confirm your registration again. This so-called "double-opt-in" procedure is used to verify your registration or to check that you are the owner of the e-mail address provided. The system also records the date and time of registration and confirmation. Your registration data is then used to send you e-mails with information about the event.MailjetMessages are sent via the Mailjet dispatch service provider (SAS Mailjet, 13-13bis, Rue de l'Aubrac - 75012 Paris, France). The Mailjet privacy policy can be found at https://www.mailjet.de/privacy-policy/.The mail delivery service provider may use your data in pseudonymous form, i.e. without allocation to a user, to optimize or improve its own services, e.g. for technical optimization of the dispatch and display of mails or for statistical purposes . The mailing service provider uses your data from the receipt of event e-mails from Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG exclusively for order processing and not to write to you personally or to pass the data on to third parties. The data you enter (e.g. e-mail address) will be stored on Mailjet servers in the EU.The legal basis is our contractual obligation pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO to provide the participant with the services owed under the contract. The dispatch service provider is appointed on the basis of a legitimate interest in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO and a contract processing agreement in accordance with Art. 28 para. 3 sentence 1 DSGVO. The purpose of collecting your e-mail address is to send you notifications about Innovation Week. The collection of other personal data as part of the registration process serves to prevent misuse of the services or the e-mail address used.The data of the Innovation Week portal will be deleted as soon as they are no longer required for the purpose of their collection. You can unsubscribe from Innovation Week at any time without giving any reason by clicking on the "Profile" tab, which will delete all data on the Innovation Week site and you will not receive any communication. TimifyFor Expert Talk (1:1), Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG uses TIMIFY from TerminApp GmbH, Balanstraße 73, in 81541 Munich, Germany, to make online appointments for a consultation. TIMIFY offers the possibility of integrating the online appointment booking on our website.TIMIFY processes and uses personal data of users (visitors, appointment bookers and service providers) of the online appointment booking facility exclusively to the extent and for the purposes described below. This is done in accordance with the applicable data protection laws.TIMIFY processes the following personal data from users of the online appointment booking facility:When calling the online appointment booking optionIf you call the online appointment booking option, your device (e.g. PC, laptop or smartphone) transmits data to TIMIFY servers for technical reasons. The following data will be transmitted for communication with your terminal device and the server of TIMIFY for the purpose of online appointment booking: Your IP addressBrowser information (name, version)Your operating system (name, version)Your screen resolutionYour browser language settingContents of the online appointment booking facility that you have accessed and called
The legal basis for the processing is the fulfilment of the contract in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO. In this context Timify acts as processor according to Art. 28 DSGVO. TIMIFY has no influence on the automatic transmission of these necessary data. Usually you have the possibility to define default settings for the transmission of information in your selected terminal device. Further information about TIMIFY can be found on the following website https://www.timify.com/de-de/pages/nutzungsbedingungen-fuer-terminbucher/ and in the TIMFIY privacy policy https://www.timify.com/de-de/legal/. Google Tag ManagerWe use the Google Tag Manager. The provider of the Google Tag Manager component is Alphabet Inc. This service allows you to manage website tags via an API. The Google Tag Manager implements only tags. This means that cookies are not used and no personal information is collected. Google Tag Manager triggers other tags that can be used to collect data. However, Google Tag Manager does not access this data. If you have been disabled on a domain or cookie basis, the disablement applies to all tracking tags if they have been implemented with Google Tag Manager.Google AnalyticsWithin the protected Innovation Week platform, we use Google Analytics for the purpose of the contractually owed service in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b DSGVO and use and evaluate the collected data additionally in order to be able to provide you with interesting content on our site and to enable personalized support . Outside of the protected area, we use Google Analytics only with your consent, which can be revoked at any time, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a DSGVO. Google Analytics is a web analysis service of Google Ireland Ltd. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which enable an analysis of your use of our websites. In this context, our order processor Google creates pseudonymized user profiles and uses cookies.Processed data: User IDBrowser type/version,Used operating system,Referrer URL (the previously visited page),Host name of the accessing terminal device (IP address, Advertising ID),Time of the server request Google Analytics is only used by us in connection with activated IP anonymization (IP masking). This means: The IP address of a user is shortened by Google for users within the member states of the European Union and other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases (e.g. in the event of a technical defect in the European Union) will the IP address be sent to a US server and shortened there.The method of anonymizing IP addresses used by Google does not write IP addresses to disk, because anonymization is performed immediately after receiving the request in memory. We do not receive any personal data from Google, only anonymized statistics.On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on the website activities and to provide further services to the website operator in connection with the use of the website and the Internet. The IP address transmitted by your browser within the scope of Google Analytics is not combined with other data from Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.Transfer to third countries (outside the EU and EEA): Google receives personal data in the course of analyzing user behavior based on your consent and processes it worldwide if necessary for the provision of services:Google Ireland LimitedGordon House, Barrow StreetDublin 4IrelandTel +353 1 543 1000Fax +353 1 686 5660E-Mail support-deutschland@google.comThe third country transfer is based on the EU standard contract clauses of Google. We store the data on pseudonymized profiles, which cannot be assigned to any individual person, for a period of 26 months to prevent cases of abuse and to optimize our websites. After the 26 months are over, this data is automatically deleted. Click here to download the browser add-on to deactivate Google Analytics. YouTubeSome of our websites use plugins from Youtube.de/youtube.com. These are operated by Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. When you visit Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG websites with such a plugin, a connection to YouTube servers is established and the plugin is displayed on the website by informing your browser. This causes cookies to be stored on your computer (VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE, PREF, YSC). Furthermore, the YouTube server is informed which of our websites you have visited. If you are registered as a member of YouTube, YouTube assigns this information to your personal user accounts on these platforms. When using these plugins, such as when clicking the start button to play a video or audio file or when sending a comment, this information is assigned to your YouTube user account. You can prevent this by logging out of YouTube before opening the file or sending a comment. The legal basis for the transmission of the information required for the selected action is our contract with you, Artl 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO. For the purpose and scope of data collection and use by Google, as well as your rights and setting options for protecting your privacy as a YouTube user, please refer to the YouTube privacy policy.
Participation in Heidelberg surveys using Microsoft Forms
The web server for the operation of our online survey is Microsoft Forms and is operated by Microsoft. Microsoft Ireland Operations LimitedOne Microsoft PlaceSouth County Industrial Park, LeopardstownDublin 18D18 P521
The data is processed on servers located in the European Union. In exceptional cases, access by Microsoft from third countries is possible. Microsoft is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield, and furthermore guarantees an adequate level of data protection through the use of the EU standard clauses: https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000KzNaAAK&status=Activehttps://www.microsoftvolumelicensing.com/DocumentSearch.aspx?Mode=3&DocumentTypeId=31
Storage duration and storage periods: The storage period of the personal data transmitted via the forms is determined by the respective processing purpose. If you do not receive additional information regarding the storage period, the retention periods stated in our general privacy information apply.
Usage data: When you access our web pages, you transmit (for technical reasons) data via your Internet browser to our web server. The following data is recorded for communication purposes between your Internet browser and our web server while a connection is established:
Date and time of request Name of requested file Page from which the file was requested Access status (file transferred, file not found, etc.) Internet browser and operating system used Full IP address of the requesting computer Transmitted quantity of data
For technical security reasons, in particular as a defense against attempted attacks on our web server, this data is temporarily stored by us. It is not possible for us to trace the data back to a specific person. The data will be anonymized after a maximum of seven days by truncating the IP address at domain level, which makes it no longer possible to establish a link to the individual user. The data is also processed in anonymized form for statistical purposes; it is neither in part nor in full matched against other databases or disclosed to third parties. Only the number of page views is shown in our server statistics, which we publish every two years in our activity report. Recipients or recipient categories As a rule, the personal data you provide will only be processed by employees of Heidelberg companies and their commissioned processors. For the fulfillment of our tasks and obligations, it may, however, become necessary for us to disclose your personal data stored to individual and legal entities, authorities, institutions, or other bodies. In particular, the following recipient categories are eligible:
Insurance companies Law enforcement agencies and courts
Microsoft Teams privacy policy
The web server for the operation of our online survey Forms is technically operated by Microsoft.
Microsoft Ireland Operations LimitedOne Microsoft Place South County Industrial Park, Leopardstown Dublin 18 D18 P521
The data is processed on servers located in the European Union. In exceptional cases, access by Microsoft from third countries is possible. https://www.microsoftvolumelicensing.com/DocumentSearch.aspx?Mode=3&DocumentTypeId=31 Purpose of processingWe use the Microsoft Teams tool to conduct telephone conferences, online meetings, video conferences and/or web conferences (in the following: “online meetings”). Microsoft Teams is a service from the Microsoft Corporation.ControllerHeidelberger Druckmaschinen AG is the controller for data processing directly related to the holding of online meetings.Note: If you access the Microsoft Teams website, the provider of Microsoft Teams is the data processing controller. However, to use Microsoft Teams, it is only necessary to access the website to download the software for using Microsoft Teams.If you do not wish to or cannot use the Microsoft Teams app, you can also use Microsoft Teams from your browser. The service is then also provided via the Microsoft Teams website.Which data is processed?When you use Microsoft Teams, different types of data are processed. The scope of the data also depends on what information you provide before or during participation in an online meeting.The following personal data is subject to processing: Information about the user: e.g. display name, e-mail address if applicable, profile picture (optional), preferred languageMeeting metadata: e.g. date, time, meeting ID, phone numbers, locationText, audio and video data: You may have the option of using the chat function in an online meeting. In this respect, the text entries made by you are processed in order to display them in the online meeting. To enable video display and audio playback, data from your terminal device's microphone and any video camera on the terminal device will be processed for the duration of the meeting. You can switch off or mute the camera or microphone yourself at any time using the Microsoft Teams applications. Scope of processingWe use Microsoft Teams in order to hold online meetings. If we want to record online meetings, we will inform you transparently in advance and – if necessary – ask for your consent.Chat content is logged when you use Microsoft Teams. Files shared by users in chats are stored in the OneDrive for Business account of the user who shared the file. Files shared by team members in a channel are stored on the team's SharePoint site.Automated decision-making within the meaning of Art. 22 GDPR is not used.Legal bases for processing the dataIf personal data is processed by employees of Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG, the legal basis for the data processing is Section 26 of the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG). If, in connection with the use of Microsoft Teams, personal data is not required for the establishment, implementation or termination of the employment relationship but is nevertheless an elementary component during the use of Microsoft Teams, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR is the legal basis for the data processing. In these cases our interest lies in the effective holding of online meetings.In all other respects, the legal basis for data processing when holding online meetings is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR, insofar as the meetings are held within the framework of contractual relationships.If no contractual relationship exists, the legal basis is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. In this case too our interest lies in the effective holding of online meetings.Recipients/Transfer of dataPersonal data that is processed in connection with participation in online meetings will not be transferred to third parties, unless the data is intended for transfer. Please note that content from online meetings and face-to-face meetings is often used to communicate information to customers, interested parties or third parties and is therefore intended for transfer.Additional recipients: The provider of Microsoft Teams necessarily obtains knowledge of the above-mentioned data to the extent that this is provided for in our commissioned processing contract with Microsoft Teams.
Contact form
If you contact us via a contact form, Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG will process your first name, last name, job title, company and number of employees, and your contact details (telephone number and e-mail address), the content of the message and, on a voluntary basis, the customer number provided. The processing of the data is carried out to deal with your request and is necessary in order to handle the request. Contact details are processed in order to respond to queries and communicate on the matter. If you are assigned to an advisor, the data will be passed on to the advisor (acting as a self-employed commercial agent) and the advisor’s employees for processing.Processing for the purpose of initiating and implementing contracts is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR. The legal basis for the processing otherwise depends on your specific request. You will find more detailed information on data protection in the context of the respective communication objectives and partners.
Job search
If you submit an application via the job search function on this website, your personal data will be processed by German service provider rexx systems GmbH (processor) on behalf of Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG (controller). The commission is contractually regulated in accordance with the legal data protection requirements for order processing (Art. 28 GDPR). Click here to read the privacy policy of the data processor. Further information on data protection is provided in the context of the application procedure or in the following document:Privacy policy for applications to Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG (pdf)
Social Media:
Social Media and Facebook
This website uses social plug-ins from Facebook, LinkedIn, Xing, Google and YouTube. These are offerings from the US companies Facebook and Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”)).We are responsible for the transmitted data together with Facebook under data protection law, but this is limited to the transmission of your communication data from our web pages to Facebook. When you visit a page containing a plug-in of this type, your browser will connect to Facebook or Google and the content will be loaded from these pages. Your visit to this website may be tracked by Facebook and Google, even if you do not actively use the social plug-in function. If you have an account with Facebook or Google, you can use a social plug-in of this type and share information with your friends. Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG has no influence on the content of the plug-ins and the transmission of information.Facebook and Google provide detailed information on the scope, type, purpose and further processing of your data on their websites, where you will also find further information on your rights and setting options to protect your privacy.Our website contains links to our Facebook fan page. If you follow these links, you will leave the website or app of the Heidelberg Group, where the Heidelberg Group is the sole data controller, and switch to a Facebook fan page where the Heidelberg Group shares the role of data controller with Facebook. The legal basis for this processing by Heidelberg is our legitimate interest in advertising our company and its services in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. For more information about Facebook’s data protection provisions, please see its privacy policy. Further information on our shared responsibility with Facebook can be found here.Facebook privacy policyGoogle privacy policy
Twitter
This website also integrates functions of the social media service Twitter. These functions are offered by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA (“Twitter”). If you use Twitter and the retweet function, the websites visited by you are linked to your Twitter account and disclosed to other users. Data is also transferred to Twitter in the process. To do this, your Internet browser establishes a direct connection to the Twitter servers and transmits data to Twitter. Please note that we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted or of its use by Twitter. Further information on this is available in Twitter’s privacy policy. You can amend your data protection settings with Twitter in the account settings.
Instagram
This website also includes plug-ins from the social network Instagram Inc, 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA (“Instagram”). You can recognize the Instagram plug-in by the Instagram button on our site.If you click the Instagram button while logged into your Instagram account, you can link the contents of our pages to your Instagram profile. This allows Instagram to associate your visit to our pages with your user account. Please note that we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted or of its use by Instagram. Please see Instagram’s privacy policy for more information.
LinkedIn
Our website uses features of the LinkedIn network. The provider is LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Every time you access one of our pages containing LinkedIn features, a connection to LinkedIn's servers is established. LinkedIn is informed that you have visited our web pages with your IP address. When you click on the LinkedIn button and are logged into your LinkedIn account, LinkedIn is able to associate your visit to our site with you and your account. Please note that, as provider of the web pages, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted or of its use by LinkedIn. The LinkedIn plug-in is used on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in achieving the widest possible degree of visibility on social media. Further information on this is available in LinkedIn’s privacy policy.
XING
Our website uses features of the XING network. The provider is XING AG, Dammtorstrasse 29-32, 20354 Hamburg, Germany. Every time you access one of our pages containing XING features, a connection to XING’s servers is established. No personal data is stored in the process, to our knowledge. In particular, no IP addresses are stored or usage behavior evaluated. The XING plug-in is used on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in achieving the widest possible degree of visibility on social media. Further information on data protection and the XING share button can be found in XING’s privacy policy.
The following services fall under the category “essential cookies”:
Consent management platform
We use a consent management platform. The service lets you decide which of the various services available on our web pages (associated with personal data processing) you wish to use only on the basis of consent. It also allows us to document your consent to the data processing and to provide the legally required proof of this. Your declaration applies to all our web pages and apps. The following data is processed: Date and time of your visitDevice informationBrowser informationAnonymized IP addressOpt-in and opt-out data The legal basis of the processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR in conjunction with Art. 7 para. 1 GDPR. Regarding data retention: All information is stored for three years from the end of processing. The legal basis for this is our obligation to document the fulfillment of the data protection requirements according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR in conjunction with Art. 5 para. 2 and Art. 24 GDPR, combined with our legitimate interest in proving compliance under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR in conjunction with Section 41 of the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG), and with Section 41 para. 2 no. 1 of the German Administrative Offenses Act (OWiG). The platform is operated by our commissioned processor, Usercentrics GmbH, Sonnenstrasse 23, 80331 Munich, Germany. You can find more information about data protection at Usercentrics here.Name: ssm_au_cProvider: UsercentricsDescription: This cookie is used to manage the cookie consent on our page and to store your preference.Expiration: Persistent until you delete cookies from your browser or changes inside the cookie consent tool are undertaken
ClickDimensions and newsletters
If you download images or click on a link in a Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG newsletter or in one of our other marketing e-mails, this is automatically logged by ClickDimensions via an e-mail tracking service. The usage information generated will be stored on our server in Germany and used for statistical usage analysis. We also use the opportunity to check whether you have opened the e-mail and which links you have clicked. Forwarded messages are tracked in the same way on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. The results help us to measure the success and reach of our newsletters and e-mails, as well as to continuously improve the content of our newsletters and make the information offered on our web pages more interesting for you.ClickDimensions never stores information in the LSO section of your computer, i.e. we never use ‘flash cookies’ (local shared objects, LSO for short). ClickDimensions does not use any visitor identification technology that involves sharing information that you provide with other websites.Data processed: IP addressContact information that you have shared with us for the provision of our servicesOpening of the e-mail or newsletterContent interactions such as image downloads or clicks on linksBrowser informationUsage dataDate and time of your visitPages viewedDevice informationDemographic information The legal basis for the processing of the personal data of users is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. In the course of this, your data may also be processed in third countries. To ensure an adequate level of data protection, we have concluded a contract with the service provider containing EU standard clauses for contract processors.If you have given your consent, we use a scoring procedure to calculate probability values according to a scientifically recognized mathematical-statistical method that is intended to help justify a possible contractual relationship with a company. This data helps with decision-making in the context of product deals, for example, and is incorporated into our risk management. In accordance with Art. 9 GDPR, information on nationality and special categories of personal data are not processed.We may also store your data for a longer period of time if necessary, for example to assert or defend legal claims, solve technical problems, or analyze security incidents.If you do not agree with the storage and analysis of this data, you can unsubscribe from the respective newsletter or by clicking on the following link, from the marketing e-mails: click here.You can find an overview of the cookies set by ClickDimensions, including the storage period, below:Name: cuvidProvider: ClickDimensionDescription: This cookie is typically written to the browser upon the first visit to the site from that web browser. If the cookie is deleted by the browser operator and the browser then visits the page, a new __cuid cookie is written. This cookie is used to identify unique visitors to the site and is updated with each page view. Additionally, this cookie is provided with a unique ID that the application uses to ensure both the validity and accessibility of the cookie as an extra security measure.Expiration: 2 years after setting/updatingName: cusidProvider: ClickDimensionDescription: This cookie is used to establish and continue a user session with the site. When a user views a page on the site, the script code attempts to update this cookie. If the cookie is not found, a new one is written and a new session established. Each time a user visits another page of the site, this cookie is updated to expire in 30 minutes. This way, a single session will continue as long as the user activity is continued within 30 minutes. This cookie expires when a user pauses on a page of the website for more than 30 minutes.Expiration: 30 mins after setting/updatingName: cuvonProvider: ClickDimensionDescription: Is used to indicate when a visitor has last viewed a page.Expiration: 30 mins after setting/updatingName: cs_optout_accountkeyProvider: ClickDimensionDescription: “accountkey” in the cookie name is a placeholder. This text would correspond to your specific account key. This cookie is generated when a visitor disables tracking. As long as it is in place, no web tracking data is generated for this visitor.Expiration: 6 months after setting/updating
Google Tag Manager
We use Google Tag Manager. The provider of the Google Tag Manager component is Alphabet Inc. This service enables website tags to be managed via an API. Google Tag Manager only implements tags. This means that cookies are not used and no personal data is collected. Google Tag Manager triggers other tags that can be used to collect data, however, Google Tag Manager does not access this data. If deactivation has been carried out at domain or cookie level, this will remain in place for all tracking tags implemented with Google Tag Manager.
Zoovu (only in PANTONE® Manager)
This is a conversation search platform and a configurator. We use Zoovu for our PANTONE® Manager, where customers can search for a color that meets their requirements.The following data is processed by Zoovu: Clicked answer (selected color)Customer IDUser identificationTime stampIP addressUsage and behavioral data (such as retrieving a color or using the search function)Events (like buying or retrieving a color) To opt out of the data processing, click here. We would like to point out that the functions of our eShop may be limited as a result.
YouTube
Some of our web pages use plug-ins from Youtube.de/youtube.com. These are operated by Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland. When you visit Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG web pages that are equipped with a plug-in of this type, a connection to YouTube servers is established and the plug-in is displayed on the page via a message to your browser. This causes cookies (VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE, PREF, YSC) to be stored on your computer. The YouTube server will then receive information as to which of our web pages you have visited. If you are registered as a YouTube member, YouTube will assign this information to your personal user accounts on these platforms. If you use these plug-ins, for example by clicking the start button to play a video or audio file or by sending a comment, this information will be associated with your YouTube user account. You can prevent this by logging out of YouTube before accessing the file or sending a comment.The information required for the selected action is transmitted on the basis of our legitimate interests in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR for the purpose of advertising products and offers from Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG.The purpose and scope of the data collection and use by Google, and your rights and setting options for protecting your privacy as a YouTube user can be found in YouTube’s privacy policy.
Podigee (only for podcasts)
To provide you with podcasts, we use the podcast hosting service of our commissioned processor Podigee UG, Am Walde 2, 56249 Herschbach, Germany. The podcasts are loaded by Podigee or transmitted via Podigee, so when you access a podcast integrated in our web pages, data is transmitted to our service provider. The use is based on our legitimate interests, i.e. our interest in the secure and efficient provision, analysis and optimization of our range of podcasts in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. Podigee processes IP addresses and device information to enable podcasts to be downloaded/played and to determine statistical data, such as download numbers. This data is anonymized or pseudonymized before being stored in Podigee’s database unless it is required for the provision of the podcasts. Data that is required for provision of the podcasts will be deleted no later than seven days after this provision if it is not required for billing purposes (see above under “How long will your data be stored?”). Click here to see Podigee’s privacy policy.
reCAPTCHA
This service (e.g. for contact forms, and newsletter registrations) is used for purposes of identification and to prevent the services provided from being misused by machines. “Captchas” are generated and verified on application servers from Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG. No data is transmitted to third parties in the process. Data processed: IP addressClick pathTime spent on the siteWebsite visitor behaviorBrowser languageUser inputJavascript objectsBrowser plug-ins The privacy policy of the data processor can be found here. Click here to opt out on all the processing company's domains.
Akamai
To optimize the loading times of our website and our online eShop application, we use a so-called content delivery network (CDN) offered by Akamai Technologies, Inc., 150 Broadway, Cambridge, MA 02142, USA. Akamai is a content delivery and cloud infrastructure service provider that coordinates and optimizes the load balancing of web content for online applications. We use Akamai services to speed up our websites so that they can provide an acceptable response time worldwide. The legal basis for the processing of users' personal data is our legitimate interest in providing an online presence that can be used worldwide without restriction in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR.Data processed: IP addressBrowser informationOperating systemPages visitedDate and time of your visit Transfer to third countries: With every processing, Akamai transfers personal data (from the log files, e.g. IP addresses) to the USA, as certain servers for processing the log files are only located in the USA. In order to ensure that this transfer of personal information from the EU to the USA complies with the data protection regulations, Akamai has been certified under the Privacy Shield program (see: https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework). Through this program, Akamai Technologies, Inc. guarantees that it complies with European data protection law. Akamai Technologies, Inc.’s privacy policy additionally applies.Information on the privacy policy of Akamai Technologies. Inc. can be found here. The company’s data protection officer can be contacted directly at the following e-mail address: privacypolicy@akamai.com
The following service falls under the category “functional cookies”:
New Relic
We use a plug-in from the New Relic web analysis service on this website. It enables us to record statistical evaluations of the speed of the website, to determine whether the website can be accessed, and how quickly the respective page is displayed when accessed. This service is operated by New Relic Inc. (188 Spear Street, Suite 1200, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA; “New Relic”).New Relic uses cookies. When you visit one of our web pages, your browser establishes a direct connection with the servers of New Relic.Through the integration of the plug-in, New Relic is informed that a user has accessed the corresponding page of our website. If the user is logged in at New Relic, New Relic can assign the visit to the user’s New Relic account. If a user is not a member of New Relic, New Relic nevertheless saves the user’s IP address. The legal basis for the processing of personal data is our legitimate interest in the evaluation of the availability and speed of our website in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. Heidelberg does not receive any personal data from New Relic, but only anonymous, statistical evaluations. Information on data protection at New Relic can also be found in New Relic’s privacy policy or you can contact the data protection officer at New Relic at the following e-mail address: mail@legislator.de.If you are a member of New Relic and do not want New Relic to collect data about you through this website and link it with your membership data stored at New Relic, you should log out of New Relic before visiting the website.
The following services fall under the category “marketing cookies”:
Google Analytics
We use Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Ireland Ltd. (“Google”) for the purpose of designing our pages to meet your needs and continuously optimizing them. This use is on the basis of your consent in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. Google Analytics uses cookies, which enable an analysis to be performed of your use of our websites and online services. In this connection, our commissioned processor Google creates pseudonymized user profiles and uses cookies. Data processed: Browser type/version,Operating system used,Referrer URL (the web page that directed you to our website),Host name of the accessing terminal device (IP address, advertising ID)Time of the server request Google Analytics is only used by us in conjunction with activated IP anonymization (IP masking). This means that users’ IP addresses are truncated by Google for users within member states of the European Union or other states party to the agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases (e.g. in the event of a technical defect in the European Union) is the IP address sent to a US server and truncated there. The IP address anonymization method used by Google does not write IP addresses to a disk, as anonymization takes place in the main memory immediately after the request is received. We do not receive any personal data from Google, only anonymized statistics.On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to analyze your use of the website, compile reports on website activities, and provide further services to the website operator in relation to the website use and Internet use. The IP address transmitted by your browser through Google Analytics is not merged with other Google data. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. Transfer to third countries (outside the EU and the EEA): Google receives personal data in the course of analyzing user behavior on the basis of your consent and processes this data worldwide if necessary for the provision of the services: Google Ireland LimitedGordon House, Barrow StreetDublin 4IrelandTel: +353 1 543 1000Fax: +353 1 686 5660E-mail: support-deutschland@google.comGoogle’s privacy policyPrivacy Shield certificationWe store the data on pseudonymized profiles that cannot be associated with any individual person for a period of 26 months to prevent cases of abuse and to optimize our web pages. This data is automatically deleted after 26 months. Move your mouse over here to opt out on all domains of the processing company or to download the browser add-on to deactivate Google Analytics. Name: _ga, _gatProvider: Google Universal Analytics Description: Both analyse browsing pattern and allow creation of flow statistics; _ga is used to distinguish individual users by means of designation of a randomly generated number as client identifier (based on browser and device), which allows calculation of visits and sessions; _gat is used to distinguish between the different monitoring objects created in the session. Expiration: _ga | Two years from settings, update or until you delete cookies from your browser; _gat | 20 minutes from settings or updateName: SourceProvider: Google Universal AnalyticsDescription: Captures the origin from where a user came on our pages.Expiration: 1 year from settings or update
Google Analytics Advertising Feature
With your consent under Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR, we use Google Analytics advertising features on our web pages. This enables us to display personal offers to you, including outside the websites hosted by Heidelberger Druckmaschinen AG. Data processed: Pages visitedIP addressDuration of the visitOther information on the use of websitesContent, in which users are interested By linking your anonymous usage data collected through Google's DoubleClick Advertising Network, we can analyze the demographic composition of our website visitors and impact on our users' interests. This helps us to present you with better and above all more relevant advertising.You can revoke your consent at any time with future effect: More information and opt-out.
Revised and posted as of November 20, 2020
Contact
How can we help you?
We look forward to your message. In order to be able to react quickly to your request, we need some information. *These fields are required.
×
Products / services
Investor relations
Career
Public relations
Number of employees* Not applicable 1-25 26-50 51-100 101-250 +250
Should we call you?
Country* Afghanistan Albania Algeria American Samoa Andorra Angola Anguilla (GB) Antigua and Barbuda Antilles Argentina Armenia Aruba Australia Austria Azerbaijan Bahamas Bahrain Bangladesh Barbados Belarus Belgium Belize Benin Bermuda Bhutan Bolivia Bonaire Bosnia Herzegovenia Botswana Brazil British Virgin Islands Brunei Bulgaria Burkina Faso Burundi Cambodia Cameroon Canada Cape Verde Cayman Islands Central African Republic Chad Channel Islands Chile China Christmas Islands Cocos Islands Colombia Comoros Congo Cook Islands Costa Rica Croatia Cuba Curacao Cyprus Czech Republic Denmark Djibouti Dominica Dominican Republic Ecuador Egypt El Salvador Equatorial Guinea Eritrea Estonia Ethiopia Falkland Islands Faroe Fiji Finland France French Guiana French Polynesia French West Indies Futuna Gabon Gambia Georgia Germany Ghana Gibraltar Greece Greenland Grenada Guadeloupe Guam Guatemala Guinea Guinea Bissau Guyana Haiti Honduras Hungary Iceland India Indonesia Iran Iraq Ireland Israel Italy Ivory Coast Jamaica Japan Jordan Kazakhstan Kenya Kiribati Korea Kuwait Kyrgyz Republic Laos Latvia Lesotho Liberia Libya Liechtenstein Lithuania Luxembourg Macau Macedonia Madagascar Malawi Malaysia Maldives Mali Malta Marshall Islands Martinique Mauritania Mauritius Mayotte Mexico Micronesia Moldova Monaco Mongolia Montenegro Montserrat Morocco Mozambique Myanmar Namibia Nauru Nepal Netherlands Netherlands Antilles New Caledonia New Zealand Nicaragua Niger Nigeria Niue Norfolk Islands Northern Mariana Islands Norway Oman Other Countries Pakistan Palau Palestine Panama Papua New Guinea Paraguay Peru Philippines Pitcairn Islands Poland Portugal Principe Puerto Rico Qatar Réunion Romania Russia Rwanda Saba Samoa (Western) San Marino São Tomé Saudi Arabia Senegal Serbia Seychelles Sierra Leone Singapore Slovakia Slovenia Solomon Islands Somalia South Africa Spain Sri Lanka St. Eustatius St. Helena St. Kitts & Nevis St. Lucia St. Maarten St. Vincent & the Grenadines Sudan Suriname Svalbard Swaziland Sweden Switzerland Syria Taiwan Tajikistan Tanzania Thailand Togo Tokelau Islands Tonga Trinidad & Tobago Tunisia Turkey Turkmenistan Turks & Caicos Islands Tuvalu Uganda Ukraine United Arab Emirates United Kingdom United States Uruguay Uzbekistan Vanuatu Vatican Venezuela Vietnam Virgin Islands (USA) Wallis Western Sahara Yemen Zambia Zimbabwe
*I have read the privacy statement and accept it. Privacy policy.
Send
